-- MySQL dump 10.13  Distrib 5.5.62, for Win64 (AMD64)
--
-- Host: localhost    Database: django
-- ------------------------------------------------------
-- Server version	5.5.62

/*!40101 SET @OLD_CHARACTER_SET_CLIENT=@@CHARACTER_SET_CLIENT */;
/*!40101 SET @OLD_CHARACTER_SET_RESULTS=@@CHARACTER_SET_RESULTS */;
/*!40101 SET @OLD_COLLATION_CONNECTION=@@COLLATION_CONNECTION */;
/*!40101 SET NAMES utf8 */;
/*!40103 SET @OLD_TIME_ZONE=@@TIME_ZONE */;
/*!40103 SET TIME_ZONE='+00:00' */;
/*!40014 SET @OLD_UNIQUE_CHECKS=@@UNIQUE_CHECKS, UNIQUE_CHECKS=0 */;
/*!40014 SET @OLD_FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS=@@FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS, FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS=0 */;
/*!40101 SET @OLD_SQL_MODE=@@SQL_MODE, SQL_MODE='NO_AUTO_VALUE_ON_ZERO' */;
/*!40111 SET @OLD_SQL_NOTES=@@SQL_NOTES, SQL_NOTES=0 */;

--
-- Table structure for table `denitrifications_app_freshwatersystem`
--

DROP TABLE IF EXISTS `denitrifications_app_freshwatersystem`;
/*!40101 SET @saved_cs_client     = @@character_set_client */;
/*!40101 SET character_set_client = utf8 */;
CREATE TABLE `denitrifications_app_freshwatersystem` (
  `id` int(11) NOT NULL AUTO_INCREMENT,
  `Influent_Source_Type` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Denitrification_System` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Denitrifying_Reactor` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Medium` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Culture` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Organism_cultured` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Respiration` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Electron_Donor` longtext NOT NULL,
  `Electron_Acceptor` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Input` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Nitrate_Removal_Rate` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Denitrification_Rate` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Microorganism_identified` longtext NOT NULL,
  `Molecular_Tools` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Major_Findings` varchar(2000) NOT NULL,
  `Authors` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Title` longtext NOT NULL,
  `Pubmed` varchar(2000) NOT NULL,
  `Link` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Abstract` longtext NOT NULL,
  PRIMARY KEY (`id`)
) ENGINE=InnoDB AUTO_INCREMENT=13 DEFAULT CHARSET=utf8;
/*!40101 SET character_set_client = @saved_cs_client */;

--
-- Dumping data for table `denitrifications_app_freshwatersystem`
--

LOCK TABLES `denitrifications_app_freshwatersystem` WRITE;
/*!40000 ALTER TABLE `denitrifications_app_freshwatersystem` DISABLE KEYS */;
INSERT INTO `denitrifications_app_freshwatersystem` VALUES (1,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Flow-through','Rotating disc','Activated sludge','Rainbow trout (Salmo gairdneri Richardson)','nan','Hydrolyzed corn starch','Nitrate','nan','30.0','nan','nan','nan','Water quality maintained by addition of hydrolysed corn starch. The trout in the recirculating system grew as well as under field conditions.','Kaiser and Schmitz (1988)','Water quality in a dosed recirculating fish culture system influenced by addition of a carbon source in relation to feed uptake by flsh','nan','https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/j.1365-2109.1988.tb00429.x','In a closed recirculating fish culture system with a rotating disc filter serving as 鈥榖iofilter鈥? waterquality was maintained by the addition of hydrolysed corn starch in the settable solids tank. According to the feed uptake by rainbow trout. Salmo gairdneri聽Richardson, starch was introduced to adjust a nutrient relation of organic C:N of 1路6:1 for the bacterial biomass. Trout grew from 42 g to 254 g in body weight in 118 days. No differences in feed uptake and feed conversion rate were observed in a control group held in a flow鈥恡hrough system with tap water as culture medium.'),(2,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Membrane-denitrification reactor (MRD)','PUR (poly(urethane))Foam cubes','nan','Carps (Cyprinus carpio)','Aerobic','Ethanol','Nitrate','nan','0.5','nan','nan','nan','Cost effective method for water purification since both processes occur in the same reactor and  no chemicals are needed to clean the membranes. The membranes remove solids thereby improving water quality. ','Boley et al., 2016','A new reactor for denitrification and micro-particle removal in recirculated aquaculture systems','https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28272049/','https://iwaponline.com/wst/article/75/5/1204/24911/A-new-reactor-for-denitrification-and','A 鈥榤embrane-denitrification鈥?reactor (MDR) was developed and tested in a semi-technical recirculation aquaculture system in comparison to a double 鈥?without MDR 鈥?as reference system. The MDR consisted of a reactor with an ultrafiltration membrane unit for removal of micro-particles (e.g. sludge flocs, bacteria and parasites). Specific carrier material provided surfaces for biofilm growth in a fluidized bed reactor with ethanol as carbon source for denitrification. The continuous motion of these carriers cleaned the membrane surface. With online and laboratory measurements of water parameters and operational data the feasibility of the concept was verified. An advantage is that no chemicals are needed to clean the membranes. Examinations of the fish and water analyses proved an MDR can positively influence cortisol, as a stress marker, and the microflora of the aquatic system.'),(3,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Self cleaning Inherent gas Denitrification reactor (SID-reactor)-Modified moving bed biofilm reactor','HDPE biocarrier St枚hr HXF12KLL','Activated sludge','Pike perch (Sander lucioperca)','Aerobic','Methanol','Nitrate','26.0','nan','450.0','nan','nan','Continuous denitrification was achieved as a result of the modfied MBBR. In this commercial recirculation aquaculture systems (RAS)clogging was prevented by recirculation of Inherent gas into the reactor.','M眉ller-Belecke et al., 2013','The 鈥渟elf cleaning inherent gas denitrification-reactor鈥?for nitrate elimination in RAS for pike perch (Sander lucioperca) production','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860913000630','Denitrification reactors have proven their functionality in commercial recirculation aquaculture systems (RAS). Nevertheless, clogging occurs due to the low hydraulic loads necessary to accomplish anoxic conditions for a successful denitrification process in RAS, which hampers the adjustment of stable working conditions within fixed bed denitrification reactors. Reactors working on the basis of activated sludge demand careful hydraulic control and/or complex configurations for sludge retention. To develop a low-maintenance denitrification reactor, an enclosed moving bed filter, driven by recirculation of the inherent, oxygen poor gas was designed. A Self cleaning Inherent gas Denitrification reactor (SID-reactor) of 0.65 m3, which offered a moving bed volume of 0.39 m3 was connected with a RAS of semi-industrial scale for pike perch (Sander lucioperca) production. This species indicates suboptimal environmental conditions (as e.g. NO3-N concentrations above approximately 68 mg l鈭?) by prompt reduction of the feed intake. In different experimental series, the SID-reactor was operated with denatured ethanol, methanol, acetic acid or glycerin as carbon sources and changing operational modes. Clogging was prevented by a 40 second inherent gas recirculation twice an hour, which provided continuous, maintenance free operation with marginal energy demand. With inlet (RAS) and outlet NO3-N concentrations in the range of 49 mg l鈭? and 12 mg l鈭?, mean denitrification rates of 199 g to 235 g NO3-N per m3 moving bed volume and day were determined for all tested carbon sources. Negative effects on the feed intake of the reared pike perch were detected with all carbon sources except methanol. Changing the mode of operation to continuous circulation of the filter bed at inlet NO3-N concentrations of 26 mg l鈭?, the denitrification performance reached 451 g NO3-N per m3 moving bed volume and day. The SID-reactor allowed for the reduction of freshwater exchange in the pike perch RAS from 600 l to 70 l (鈭?8%) and the sodium bicarbonate buffer from 182 g to 31 g (鈭?3%) per kg of administered food. The easy and reliable operation of the SID-reactor could help to establish controlled denitrification as a routine purification step in RAS'),(4,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Autotrophic Denitrification','Reticulated sponge','Polyurethane','Within the systems','Southern platyfish (Xiphophorus maculatus)','Anaerobic','Hydrogen','Nitrate','20.0','nan','36.0','nan','nan','Hydrogenotrophic denitrification reactor was designed and applied in the removal of nitrate from aquaria system. Hydrogen gas was used as an electron donor because it is not toxic and gets less microbial biomass compared to traditional electron donors.','Grommen et al., 2006','Removal of nitrate in aquaria by means of electrochemically generated hydrogen gas as electron donor for biological denitrification','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860905000397','A hydrogenotrophic聽denitrification聽reactor was designed for the removal of nitrate from aquaria. An average hydrogen gas transfer up to 130聽mg per day from the gas to the water phase was accomplished by recirculating the water from the denitrification reactor over a separate trickling filter column with a volume of 1.3聽l. During batch experiments removal rates up to 36聽mg聽N/l reactor per day were recorded at a hydraulic residence time of 12聽h. To avoid the need for storage of large volumes of hydrogen gas in aquarium or聽aquaculture聽applications, an electrochemical cell was used to generate hydrogen gas. During a 7 day aquarium test, a nitrate removal rate up to 18.5聽mg聽N/l reactor per day was recorded at an influent NO3鈭掆€揘 concentration of 20聽mg/l.'),(5,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','Plastic media bed','Within the systems','Siberian sturgeon (Acipenser baeri)','Aerobic','Molasses','Nitrate','50.0','nan','670.0','nan','nan','Molasses can be an attractive alternate carbon source because of its low cost. However there is need to resolve problems associated with carbon source such as ammonia production, turbidity and foaming.','Hamlin et al., 2008','Comparing denitrification rates and carbon sources in commercial scale upflow denitrification biological filters in aquaculture','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860907000970','Aerobic biological filtration systems employing nitrifying bacteria to remediate excess ammonia and nitrite concentrations are common components of recirculating aquaculture systems (RAS). However, significant water exchange may still be necessary to reduce nitrate concentrations to acceptable levels unless denitrification systems are included in the RAS design. This study evaluated the design of a full scale denitrification reactor in a commercial culture RAS application. Four carbon sources were evaluated including methanol, acetic acid, molasses and Cerelose鈩? a hydrolyzed starch, to determine their applicability under commercial culture conditions and to determine if any of these carbon sources encouraged the production of two common 鈥渙ff-flavor鈥?compounds, 2-methyisoborneol (MIB) or geosmin. The denitrification design consisted of a 1.89聽m3聽covered conical bottom polyethylene tank containing 1.0聽m3聽media through which water up-flowed at a rate of 10聽lpm. A commercial aquaculture system housing 6 metric tonnes of Siberian sturgeon was used to generate nitrate through nitrification in a moving bed biological filter. All four carbon sources were able to effectively reduce nitrate to near zero concentrations from influent concentrations ranging from 11 to 57聽mg/l NO3鈥揘, and the maximum daily denitrification rate was 670鈥?80聽g聽nitrogen聽removed/m3聽media/day, regardless of the carbon source. Although nitrite production was not a problem once the reactors achieved a constant effluent nitrate, ammonia production was a significant problem for units fed molasses and to a less extent Cerelose鈩? Maximum measured ammonia concentrations in the reactor effluents for methanol, vinegar, Cerelose鈩?and molasses were 1.62聽卤聽0.10, 2.83聽卤聽0.17, 4.55聽卤聽0.45 and 5.25聽卤聽1.26聽mg/l NH3鈥揘, respectively. Turbidity production was significantly increased in reactors fed molasses and to a less extent Cerelose鈩? Concentrations of geosmin and MIB were not significantly increased in any of the denitrification reactors, regardless of carbon source. Because of its very low cost compared to the other sources tested, molasses may be an attractive carbon source for denitrification if issues of ammonia production, turbidity and foaming can be resolved.'),(6,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','Polyethylene','nan','Eel','Aerobic','Methanol','Nitrate','150.0','1.8','43.0','nan','nan','The closed recirculating system applied in this study brings environmental load close to zero and has the potential to be applied in freshwater systems as a novel aquaculture technology.','Suzuki et al., 2003','Performance of a closed recirculating system with foam separation, nitrification and denitrification units for intensive culture of eel: towards zero emission','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860903000840','The development of a closed recirculating aquaculture system that does not discharge effluents would reduce a large amount of pollutant load on aquatic bodies. In this study, eel were reared in a closed recirculating system, which consisted of a rearing tank, a foam separation unit, a nitrification unit and a denitrification unit. The foam separation unit has an inhalation-type aerator and supplies air bubbles to the rearing water. The growth of eel, which were fed a commercial diet, was satisfactory, with gross weight increases of up three times in 3 months. The survival rate under the congested experimental conditions was 91%. The foam separation unit maintained oxygen saturation in the rearing water at about 80%. Furthermore, fine colloidal substances were absorbed on the stable foam formed from eel mucus and were removed from the rearing water by foam separation. Ammonia oxidation and the removal of suspended solids were accomplished rapidly and simultaneously in the nitrification unit. The ammonia concentration and turbidity were kept at less than 1.2聽mg of N per litre and 2.5 units, respectively. When the denitrification process was operated, nitrate that accumulated in the rearing water (151聽mg of N per litre) was reduced to 40聽mg of N per litre. The sludge was easily recovered from the nitrification and denitrification tanks, and the components were found suitable as compost. Based on these results, the intensive aquaculture of freshwater fish such as eel can be achieved using a closed recirculating system without emission.'),(7,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','Plastic media bed','Water from Sturgeon culture','Siberian sturgeon (Acipenser baeri)','Aerobic','Hydrolyzed starch','Nitrate','50.0','nan','680.0','nan','nan','Molasses can be an attractive alternate carbon source because of its low cost. However there is need to resolve problems associated with carbon source such as ammonia production, turbidity and foaming.','Hamlin et al., 2008','Comparing denitrification rates and carbon sources in commercial scale upflow denitrification biological filters in aquaculture','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860907000970','Aerobic biological filtration systems employing nitrifying bacteria to remediate excess ammonia and nitrite concentrations are common components of recirculating aquaculture systems (RAS). However, significant water exchange may still be necessary to reduce nitrate concentrations to acceptable levels unless denitrification systems are included in the RAS design. This study evaluated the design of a full scale denitrification reactor in a commercial culture RAS application. Four carbon sources were evaluated including methanol, acetic acid, molasses and Cerelose鈩? a hydrolyzed starch, to determine their applicability under commercial culture conditions and to determine if any of these carbon sources encouraged the production of two common 鈥渙ff-flavor鈥?compounds, 2-methyisoborneol (MIB) or geosmin. The denitrification design consisted of a 1.89聽m3聽covered conical bottom polyethylene tank containing 1.0聽m3聽media through which water up-flowed at a rate of 10聽lpm. A commercial aquaculture system housing 6 metric tonnes of Siberian sturgeon was used to generate nitrate through nitrification in a moving bed biological filter. All four carbon sources were able to effectively reduce nitrate to near zero concentrations from influent concentrations ranging from 11 to 57聽mg/l NO3鈥揘, and the maximum daily denitrification rate was 670鈥?80聽g聽nitrogen聽removed/m3聽media/day, regardless of the carbon source. Although nitrite production was not a problem once the reactors achieved a constant effluent nitrate, ammonia production was a significant problem for units fed molasses and to a less extent Cerelose鈩? Maximum measured ammonia concentrations in the reactor effluents for methanol, vinegar, Cerelose鈩?and molasses were 1.62聽卤聽0.10, 2.83聽卤聽0.17, 4.55聽卤聽0.45 and 5.25聽卤聽1.26聽mg/l NH3鈥揘, respectively. Turbidity production was significantly increased in reactors fed molasses and to a less extent Cerelose鈩? Concentrations of geosmin and MIB were not significantly increased in any of the denitrification reactors, regardless of carbon source. Because of its very low cost compared to the other sources tested, molasses may be an attractive carbon source for denitrification if issues of ammonia production, turbidity and foaming can be resolved.'),(8,'Aquaculture wastewater','Fish-culture systems','Fluidized','Alginate beads','Pseudomonas sp. JR12',' Goldfish (Carassius auratus)','nan','Immobilized starch','Nitrate','nan','nan','624.0','nan','nan','Alginate beads containing an immobilized denitrifying bacterium and  immobilized starch can be used for removal of nitrate from water systems.','Tal et al., 2003','Nitrate Removal in Aquariums by Immobilized聽Pseudomonas','https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12790671/','https://aiche.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1021/bp0200088','Biological denitrification of nitrate to nitrogen gas was examined in a freshwater and a marine aquarium. Nitrate removal in the aquarium water was accomplished with denitrifiers immobilized in a freeze鈥恉ried, alginate鈥恠tarch matrix. Starch served as a bacterial carbon source and cellular matrix鈥恠trengthening filler. Freeze鈥恉ried beads were placed in canisters through which nitrate鈥恟ich aquarium water was recirculated. The freshwater aquarium (100 L) contained goldfish (Carassius auratus聽) at a total biomass of 390 g, whereas cichlids (Oreochromis mossambicus聽) were kept at a similar stocking density in the marine aquarium. Denitrification resulted in low ambient nitrate concentrations in both aquariums. The specific nitrate removal rate of the freshwater beads was significantly higher (50 渭g of NO3鈥怤/bead/day) than that of seawater beads (5 渭g of NO3鈥怤/bead/day). Differences in ambient nitrate concentrations between both aquariums and diffusion limitation of nitrate to the active denitrification sites within the beads might explain these observed differences.'),(9,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','Plastic media bed','Within the systems','Siberian sturgeon (Acipenser baeri)','Aerobic','Methanol','Nitrate','50.0','nan','670.0','nan','nan','Molasses can be an attractive alternate carbon source because of its low cost. However there is need to resolve problems associated with carbon source such as ammonia production, turbidity and foaming.','Hamlin et al., 2008','Comparing denitrification rates and carbon sources in commercial scale upflow denitrification biological filters in aquaculture','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860907000970','Aerobic biological filtration systems employing nitrifying bacteria to remediate excess ammonia and nitrite concentrations are common components of recirculating aquaculture systems (RAS). However, significant water exchange may still be necessary to reduce nitrate concentrations to acceptable levels unless denitrification systems are included in the RAS design. This study evaluated the design of a full scale denitrification reactor in a commercial culture RAS application. Four carbon sources were evaluated including methanol, acetic acid, molasses and Cerelose鈩? a hydrolyzed starch, to determine their applicability under commercial culture conditions and to determine if any of these carbon sources encouraged the production of two common 鈥渙ff-flavor鈥?compounds, 2-methyisoborneol (MIB) or geosmin. The denitrification design consisted of a 1.89聽m3聽covered conical bottom polyethylene tank containing 1.0聽m3聽media through which water up-flowed at a rate of 10聽lpm. A commercial aquaculture system housing 6 metric tonnes of Siberian sturgeon was used to generate nitrate through nitrification in a moving bed biological filter. All four carbon sources were able to effectively reduce nitrate to near zero concentrations from influent concentrations ranging from 11 to 57聽mg/l NO3鈥揘, and the maximum daily denitrification rate was 670鈥?80聽g聽nitrogen聽removed/m3聽media/day, regardless of the carbon source. Although nitrite production was not a problem once the reactors achieved a constant effluent nitrate, ammonia production was a significant problem for units fed molasses and to a less extent Cerelose鈩? Maximum measured ammonia concentrations in the reactor effluents for methanol, vinegar, Cerelose鈩?and molasses were 1.62聽卤聽0.10, 2.83聽卤聽0.17, 4.55聽卤聽0.45 and 5.25聽卤聽1.26聽mg/l NH3鈥揘, respectively. Turbidity production was significantly increased in reactors fed molasses and to a less extent Cerelose鈩? Concentrations of geosmin and MIB were not significantly increased in any of the denitrification reactors, regardless of carbon source. Because of its very low cost compared to the other sources tested, molasses may be an attractive carbon source for denitrification if issues of ammonia production, turbidity and foaming can be resolved.'),(10,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','Plastic media bed','Within the systems','Siberian sturgeon (Acipenser baeri)','Aerobic','Acetic acid','Nitrate','50.0','nan','670.0','nan','nan','Molasses can be an attractive alternate carbon source because of its low cost. However there is need to resolve problems associated with carbon source such as ammonia production, turbidity and foaming.','Hamlin et al., 2008','Comparing denitrification rates and carbon sources in commercial scale upflow denitrification biological filters in aquaculture','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860907000970','Aerobic biological filtration systems employing nitrifying bacteria to remediate excess ammonia and nitrite concentrations are common components of recirculating aquaculture systems (RAS). However, significant water exchange may still be necessary to reduce nitrate concentrations to acceptable levels unless denitrification systems are included in the RAS design. This study evaluated the design of a full scale denitrification reactor in a commercial culture RAS application. Four carbon sources were evaluated including methanol, acetic acid, molasses and Cerelose鈩? a hydrolyzed starch, to determine their applicability under commercial culture conditions and to determine if any of these carbon sources encouraged the production of two common 鈥渙ff-flavor鈥?compounds, 2-methyisoborneol (MIB) or geosmin. The denitrification design consisted of a 1.89聽m3聽covered conical bottom polyethylene tank containing 1.0聽m3聽media through which water up-flowed at a rate of 10聽lpm. A commercial aquaculture system housing 6 metric tonnes of Siberian sturgeon was used to generate nitrate through nitrification in a moving bed biological filter. All four carbon sources were able to effectively reduce nitrate to near zero concentrations from influent concentrations ranging from 11 to 57聽mg/l NO3鈥揘, and the maximum daily denitrification rate was 670鈥?80聽g聽nitrogen聽removed/m3聽media/day, regardless of the carbon source. Although nitrite production was not a problem once the reactors achieved a constant effluent nitrate, ammonia production was a significant problem for units fed molasses and to a less extent Cerelose鈩? Maximum measured ammonia concentrations in the reactor effluents for methanol, vinegar, Cerelose鈩?and molasses were 1.62聽卤聽0.10, 2.83聽卤聽0.17, 4.55聽卤聽0.45 and 5.25聽卤聽1.26聽mg/l NH3鈥揘, respectively. Turbidity production was significantly increased in reactors fed molasses and to a less extent Cerelose鈩? Concentrations of geosmin and MIB were not significantly increased in any of the denitrification reactors, regardless of carbon source. Because of its very low cost compared to the other sources tested, molasses may be an attractive carbon source for denitrification if issues of ammonia production, turbidity and foaming can be resolved.'),(11,'Aquaculture wastewater','RAS Sulfur-driven denitrification (SDN) systems','Fluidized ','Sulfur biofilters','Waste sludge from the production of rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss) and Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar)','聽Rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss); Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar)','Anaerobic','Sulfur ','Nitrate','nan','nan','nan','Consortium of denitrifying bacteria','Functional gene identification based on nosZ gene','The effectiveness of autotrophic, sulphur-based denitrification reactors as an alternative to conventional heterotrophic denitrification reactors was explored because autotrophic reactors produce less biomass (solids) and can be supplied with sulphur particles, which are cheaper than conventional inorganic carbon sources.','Christianson et al., 2015','Nitrate removal effectiveness of fluidized sulfur-based autotrophic denitrification biofilters for recirculating aquaculture systems','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0144860915000527','There is a need to develop practical methods to reduce nitrate鈥搉itrogen loads from recirculating aquaculture systems to facilitate increased food protein production simultaneously with attainment of water quality goals. The most common wastewater denitrification treatment systems utilize methanol-fueled heterotrophs, but sulfur-based autotrophic denitrification may allow a shift away from potentially expensive carbon sources. The objective of this work was to assess the nitrate-reduction potential of fluidized sulfur-based biofilters for treatment of aquaculture wastewater. Three fluidized biofilters (height 3.9聽m, diameter 0.31聽m; operational volume 0.206聽m3) were filled with sulfur particles (0.30聽mm effective particle size; static bed depth approximately 0.9聽m) and operated in triplicate mode (Phase I: 37鈥?9% expansion; 3.2鈥?.3聽min hydraulic retention time; 860鈥?88聽L/(m2聽min) hydraulic loading rate) and independently to achieve a range of hydraulic retention times (Phase II: 42鈥?3% expansion; 3.2鈥?.8聽min hydraulic retention time). During Phase I, despite only removing 1.57聽卤聽0.15 and 1.82聽卤聽0.32聽mg NO3鈥揘/L each pass through the biofilter, removal rates were the highest reported for sulfur-based denitrification systems (0.71聽卤聽0.07 and 0.80聽卤聽0.15聽g聽N removed/(L bioreactor-d)). Lower than expected sulfate production and alkalinity consumption indicated some of the nitrate removal was due to heterotrophic denitrification, and thus denitrification was mixotrophic. Microbial analysis indicated the presence of聽Thiobacillus denitrificans, a widely known autotrophic denitrifier, in addition to several heterotrophic denitrifiers. Phase II showed that longer retention times tended to result in more nitrate removal and sulfate production, but increasing the retention time through flow rate manipulation may create fluidization challenges for these sulfur particles.'),(12,'Aquaculture wastewater','Hetetrophic denitrification','Fluidized ','Sand biofilters','Waste sludge from the production of rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss) and Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar)','聽Rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss); Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar)','Anaerobic','Waste-based endogenous carbon source','Nitrate','nan','3.9','nan','Consortium of denitrifying bacteria','Functional gene identification based on nosZ gene','Heterotrophic denitrification in fluidized sand biofilters using a waste-based endogenous carbon source proved to be an effective technology to remove NO3-N from the effluent of a land-based closed-containment aquaculture system. ','Tsukuda et al., 2015','Heterotrophic denitrification of aquaculture effluent using fluidized sand biofilters','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0144860914001137','The ability to consistently and cost-effectively reduce nitrate-nitrogen loads in effluent from recirculating aquaculture systems would enhance the industry\'s environmental stewardship and allow improved facility proximity to large markets in sensitive watersheds. Heterotrophic denitrification technologies specifically employing organic carbon found in aquaculture system waste offer a unique synergy for treatment of land-based, closed-containment production outflows. For space-efficient fluidized sand biofilters to be used as such denitrification reactors, system parameters (e.g., influent dissolved oxygen and carbon to nitrogen ratios, C:N) must be evaluated to most effectively use an endogenous carbon source. The objectives of this work were to quantify nitrate removal under a range of C:Ns and to explore the biofilter bacterial community using three replicated fluidized sand biofilters (height 3.9聽m, diameter 0.31聽m; fluidized sand volume plus biofilm volume of 0.206聽m3) operated at a hydraulic retention time of 15聽min and a hydraulic loading rate of 188聽L/min聽m2聽at The Conservation Fund Freshwater Institute in Shepherdstown, West Virginia, USA. Nitrate reduction was consistently observed during the biofilter study period (26.9聽卤聽0.9% removal efficiency; 402聽卤聽14聽g NO3-N/(m3聽biofilter聽d)) although nitrite-N and total ammonium nitrogen concentrations slightly increased (11 and 13% increases, respectively). Nitrate removal efficiency was correlated with carbonaceous oxygen demand to nitrate ratios (R2聽>聽0.70). Nitrate removal rates during the study period were moderately negatively correlated with influent dissolved oxygen concentration indicating it may be possible the biofilter hydraulic retention time was too short to provide optimized nitrate removal. It is reasonable to assume that the efficiency of nitrate removal across the fluidized sand biofilters could be substantially increased, as long as organic carbon was not limiting, by increasing biofilter bed depths (to 6鈥?0聽m), and thus hydraulic retention time. These findings provide a low-cost yet effective technology to remove nitrate-nitrogen from effluent waters of land-based closed-containment aquaculture systems.');
/*!40000 ALTER TABLE `denitrifications_app_freshwatersystem` ENABLE KEYS */;
UNLOCK TABLES;
/*!40103 SET TIME_ZONE=@OLD_TIME_ZONE */;

/*!40101 SET SQL_MODE=@OLD_SQL_MODE */;
/*!40014 SET FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS=@OLD_FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS */;
/*!40014 SET UNIQUE_CHECKS=@OLD_UNIQUE_CHECKS */;
/*!40101 SET CHARACTER_SET_CLIENT=@OLD_CHARACTER_SET_CLIENT */;
/*!40101 SET CHARACTER_SET_RESULTS=@OLD_CHARACTER_SET_RESULTS */;
/*!40101 SET COLLATION_CONNECTION=@OLD_COLLATION_CONNECTION */;
/*!40111 SET SQL_NOTES=@OLD_SQL_NOTES */;

-- Dump completed on 2020-06-29  8:47:45
