-- MySQL dump 10.13  Distrib 5.5.62, for Win64 (AMD64)
--
-- Host: localhost    Database: django
-- ------------------------------------------------------
-- Server version	5.5.62

/*!40101 SET @OLD_CHARACTER_SET_CLIENT=@@CHARACTER_SET_CLIENT */;
/*!40101 SET @OLD_CHARACTER_SET_RESULTS=@@CHARACTER_SET_RESULTS */;
/*!40101 SET @OLD_COLLATION_CONNECTION=@@COLLATION_CONNECTION */;
/*!40101 SET NAMES utf8 */;
/*!40103 SET @OLD_TIME_ZONE=@@TIME_ZONE */;
/*!40103 SET TIME_ZONE='+00:00' */;
/*!40014 SET @OLD_UNIQUE_CHECKS=@@UNIQUE_CHECKS, UNIQUE_CHECKS=0 */;
/*!40014 SET @OLD_FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS=@@FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS, FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS=0 */;
/*!40101 SET @OLD_SQL_MODE=@@SQL_MODE, SQL_MODE='NO_AUTO_VALUE_ON_ZERO' */;
/*!40111 SET @OLD_SQL_NOTES=@@SQL_NOTES, SQL_NOTES=0 */;

--
-- Table structure for table `denitrifications_app_marinesystem`
--

DROP TABLE IF EXISTS `denitrifications_app_marinesystem`;
/*!40101 SET @saved_cs_client     = @@character_set_client */;
/*!40101 SET character_set_client = utf8 */;
CREATE TABLE `denitrifications_app_marinesystem` (
  `id` int(11) NOT NULL AUTO_INCREMENT,
  `Influent_Source_Type` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Denitrification_System` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Denitrifying_Reactor` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Medium` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Culture` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Organism_cultured` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Respiration` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Electron_Donor` longtext NOT NULL,
  `Electron_Acceptor` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Input` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Nitrate_Removal_Rate` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Denitrification_Rate` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Microorganism_identified` longtext NOT NULL,
  `Molecular_Tools` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Major_Findings` varchar(2000) NOT NULL,
  `Authors` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Title` longtext NOT NULL,
  `Pubmed` varchar(2000) NOT NULL,
  `Link` varchar(200) NOT NULL,
  `Abstract` longtext NOT NULL,
  PRIMARY KEY (`id`)
) ENGINE=InnoDB AUTO_INCREMENT=15 DEFAULT CHARSET=utf8;
/*!40101 SET character_set_client = @saved_cs_client */;

--
-- Dumping data for table `denitrifications_app_marinesystem`
--

LOCK TABLES `denitrifications_app_marinesystem` WRITE;
/*!40000 ALTER TABLE `denitrifications_app_marinesystem` DISABLE KEYS */;
INSERT INTO `denitrifications_app_marinesystem` VALUES (1,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems','Membrane biofilm reactor','Polyethylene (PE) and poly(ethylene-vinyl acetate) (EVA)','nan','Small fishes and Lobster','Aerobic','Ethanol','Nitrate','20-40','nan','82','nan','nan','It has the practical benefit of eliminating the need for a pump for ethanol supply and an additional loop or tank exclusively for denitrification.','Shoji et al., 2014','Demonstration of a novel ethanol-packed membrane biofilm reactor for denitrification at the Tokyo Sea Life Park','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860914000922','A novel ethanol-packed membrane biofilm reactor (MBfR) was used to develop a simple denitrification technology applicable to aerobic tanks in recirculating aquarium or aquaculture systems. First, the basic properties of the module of the MBfR were assessed via a series of batch tests. The results of the batch tests indicated that (1) the module could obtain denitrifying capability after a 2-week submergence in aerated seawater without having direct inoculation onto the module, (2) the denitrification rate was proportional to the ethanol supply rate, and (3) the type of supporting medium had little effect on denitrifying capability. On the basis of these results, a module for the full-scale demonstration was made of 30聽cm聽脳聽30聽cm square of non-woven fabric coated with a 0.07-mm-thick PE film on the one side. An openable tap was incorporated to supply additional ethanol, and 100聽mL of ethanol was packed into each module before use. Then, the appropriate number of modules was used for a full-scale demonstration in two types of recirculating aquarium systems for up to 400 days. In an aquarium rearing small fishes, the three MBfR modules submerged in the aerobic tank prevented nitrate accumulation for 77 days. However, the surface denitrification rate (0.68聽gN聽m鈭?聽d鈭?) was smaller than the expected value, probably because the nitrate concentration was very low. In another aquarium mainly rearing lobsters, the 17 submerged modules prevented nitrate accumulation at the rate of 1.0鈥?.1聽gN聽m鈭?聽d鈭?聽for approximately 6 months without ethanol refilling. After that, it was also observed that the dilution of ethanol decreased the denitrification rate; however, ethanol refilling resulted in immediate recovery of denitrification capability. Taken together, our results indicate that the proposed ethanol-packed MBfR could be employed as a denitrification technology for recirculating aquariums or aquacultures, and offers the practical advantage of eliminating the need for a pump for ethanol supply and an additional loop or tank exclusively for denitrification.'),(2,'Aquaculture wastewater','Recirculating aquaculture systems','Membrane biofilm reactor','Polyethylene (PE) and poly(ethylene-vinyl acetate) (EVA)','nan','Small fishes and Lobster','Aerobic','Ethanol','Nitrate','nan','nan','82','nan','nan','It has the practical benefit of eliminating the need for a pump for ethanol supply and an additional loop or tank exclusively for denitrification.','Shoji et al., 2014','Demonstration of a novel ethanol-packed membrane biofilm reactor for denitrification at the Tokyo Sea Life Park','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860914000922','A novel ethanol-packed membrane biofilm reactor (MBfR) was used to develop a simple denitrification technology applicable to aerobic tanks in recirculating aquarium or aquaculture systems. First, the basic properties of the module of the MBfR were assessed via a series of batch tests. The results of the batch tests indicated that (1) the module could obtain denitrifying capability after a 2-week submergence in aerated seawater without having direct inoculation onto the module, (2) the denitrification rate was proportional to the ethanol supply rate, and (3) the type of supporting medium had little effect on denitrifying capability. On the basis of these results, a module for the full-scale demonstration was made of 30聽cm聽脳聽30聽cm square of non-woven fabric coated with a 0.07-mm-thick PE film on the one side. An openable tap was incorporated to supply additional ethanol, and 100聽mL of ethanol was packed into each module before use. Then, the appropriate number of modules was used for a full-scale demonstration in two types of recirculating aquarium systems for up to 400 days. In an aquarium rearing small fishes, the three MBfR modules submerged in the aerobic tank prevented nitrate accumulation for 77 days. However, the surface denitrification rate (0.68聽gN聽m鈭?聽d鈭?) was smaller than the expected value, probably because the nitrate concentration was very low. In another aquarium mainly rearing lobsters, the 17 submerged modules prevented nitrate accumulation at the rate of 1.0鈥?.1聽gN聽m鈭?聽d鈭?聽for approximately 6 months without ethanol refilling. After that, it was also observed that the dilution of ethanol decreased the denitrification rate; however, ethanol refilling resulted in immediate recovery of denitrification capability. Taken together, our results indicate that the proposed ethanol-packed MBfR could be employed as a denitrification technology for recirculating aquariums or aquacultures, and offers the practical advantage of eliminating the need for a pump for ethanol supply and an additional loop or tank exclusively for denitrification.'),(3,'Mesocosm seawater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Submerged moving bed biofilm reactor (MBBR)','Polyethylene','Cosed-circuit aquarium','nan','Anaerobic','Methanol','Nitrate','22','nan','1700','nan','nan','MBBR was efficient at denitrifying saltwater containing a high sulfate concentration and was effective at resisting H2S toxicity shock, limiting thickness of biofilm thereby preventing carrier fouling and the rate of denitrification rates was controllable.','Labelle et., 2005','Seawater denitrification in a closed mesocosm by a submerged moving bed biofilm reactor.','https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16023699/','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0043135405003052','The performance of a submerged moving bed biofilm reactor (MBBR) for the denitrification of seawater in a 3.25 million聽l closed circuit mesocosm was investigated at pilot scale, using methanol as a carbon source at various C/N ratios. Nitrate accumulation in closed systems where water changes are expensive and problematic may cause toxicity problems to marine life. Seawater was pretreated in a recirculated fixed bed to remove oxygen prior to the denitrification step. The 110聽l MBBR was partly filled (25%) with spherical positively buoyant polyethylene carriers with an effective surface area of approximately 100聽m2聽m鈭?, which represents 35% of the total surface area. Carriers were maintained submerged by a conical grid and circulated by the downflow jet of an eductor. The MBBR mixing system was designed to prevent dead mixing zones and carrier fouling to avoid sulfate reduction while treating seawater containing as high as 2150聽mg SO4-S聽l鈭?. NO3-N reduction from 53 to as low as 1.7卤0.7聽mg聽l鈭?聽and a maximum denitrification rate of 17.7卤1.4聽g N聽m鈭?聽d鈭?聽were achieved at 4.2鈥?.3 applied COD/N (w/w) ratio. Methanol consumption corresponded to denitrification stoichiometric values, indicating the absence of sulfate reduction. Denitrification rates and effluent residual dissolved organic carbon were proportional to the C/N ratio. Such reactors could be scaled up in closed systems where water changes must be minimized.'),(4,'Seawater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','Stationary filament biofilter substrate (BIOPOLYMA鈩?','Bacillus sp.','Black tiger shrimp (Penaeus monodon)','Aerobic','Ethanol/methanol','Nitrate','165','nan','158','nan','nan','The denitrification system was modified (carbon source, substrate and hydraulic residence time) which enhanced the removal of nitrate and the system\'s pH was stabilized improving the water quality. The shrimp grew quite well','Menasveta et al., 2001','Design and function of a closed, recirculating seawater system with denitrification for the culture of black tiger shrimp broodstock.','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860901000693','A closed, recirculating seawater system with a denitrification process was designed for the culture of black tiger shrimp broodstock. The system comprised a circular rearing tank (9 m3聽volume), a nitrifying biofilter (6 m3聽volume) and denitrification process. The denitrification process comprised a deoxygenation column, a bacterial substrate column (143 L volume) and a re-aeration column connected to the biofilter. The experimental period was 81 weeks, consisting of 3 sequential trials using different substrates, bacterial inoculates and carbon sources: Trial 1- porous plastic balls for substrate, mangrove soil for inoculant and ethanol for the carbon source; Trial 2- crushed oyster shell for substrate, a strain of laboratory cultured bacteria for inoculant and ethanol for the carbon source; and Trial 3- crushed oyster shell for the substrate, no inoculant and methanol for the carbon source. The nitrifying biofilter controlled ammonium-N聽and nitrite-N聽within acceptable ranges (<0.5 and <0.2 mg L鈭?, respectively). The nitrate-N, however, became elevated gradually during trial 1 (<50 mg L鈭?). During trial 2, modification of bacterial substrate and the inoculation with denitrifying bacteria reduced nitrate-N聽in the denitrification column and the rearing tank (p<0.05). Changing the carbon source to methanol and increasing the hydraulic residence time in trial 3 resulted in a significant reduction (P<0.05) in nitrate-N聽(from >160 to <25 mg l鈭?) without the need for bacterial inoculation.'),(5,'Seawater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','Polyvinyl alcohol(PVA) with hydrolyzed collagen (HC)','Activated sludge','nan','Anaerobic','Glucose','Nitrate','3.5','nan','34','nan','nan','In developing and optimizing the marine recirculating system, study found out that addition or increased salt concentration inhibits denitrification and a reduction in hydraulic retention time increases the rate of nitrate removal with denitrification efficiency being reduced.','Park et al., 2001','Salinity acclimation of immobilized freshwater denitrifier.','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860901000620','To develop a marine recirculating aquarium system, the marine denitrification process was evaluated for the effects of salinity, temperature and hydraulic retention time (HRT) on marine denitrification processes. Denitrifier consortium was collected from a continuous denitrification tank operated for 120 days and was immobilized by the PVA-boric acid method. Four reactors were simultaneously operated to determine the effect of salinity. One of them, R-1, was supplied with tap water as a control. and others, R-2, R-3 and R-4 were supplied with sea water diluted with tap water by 3 steps (7.5, 15, 30 ppt), 2 steps (15, 30 ppt) and 1 step (30 ppt), respectively. The loading rate of nitrate-nitrogen averaged 20.6 g/m3/day. Salinity caused nitrite-nitrogen formation at the early stage of acclimation, even though the conversion rates of nitrate for high salinites were similar to that of the control (freshwater). Addition of salt to the system might cause a damage to denitrifiers that convert nitrate to nitrogen gas, however the activity was recovered after 10 days of operation. Also, the direct acclimation method to seawater was more efficient than the stepwise acclimation method when the freshwater denitrification system was converted to the marine system. As the HRT was reduced, the nitrate removal rate increased and denitrification efficiency decreased. The optimum HRT was 3 h with a nitrate removal rate of 34 g/m3/day. Any further decrease in HRT decreased the nitrate removal rate due to the rapid drop of nitrate removal efficiency and high flow rate.'),(6,'Ocean tank','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','nan','Bacteria (of the genus Pseudomonas)','nan','Anaerobic','Methanol','Nitrate','40-130','nan','180-200','nan','nan','The system developed can applied for modelling carbon and nitrogen flux studies in closed marine water systems in which heterotrophic organisms are hosted. ','Grguric et al., 2000b','Carbon and nitrogen fluxes in a closed seawater facility.','https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10721143/','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0048969799004696','A variety of empirical and calculated data from the largest tank at the New Jersey State Aquarium were used to quantify the fluxes of carbon and nitrogen before and after the installation of denitrification in this facility. Before denitrification, the stock of dissolved inorganic carbon (DIC) in Ocean Tank exhibited a decrease of 6.9 kg C/month and sodium bicarbonate had to be added to maintain DIC in steady state. We were able to explain the DIC decrease by two non-conservative processes: the formation of carbonaceous precipitates (removes 4.2 kg C/month) and outgassing of carbon dioxide due to acidity from nitrification (independently determined to remove 3.2 kg C/month). Nitrogen budget in Ocean Tank before denitrification is in contrast to that of carbon, and it shows an increase of 4.8 kg N/month in the form of nitrate. Denitrification is currently removing 53.3 kg N/month (in the form of nitrogen gas), so this element should eventually reach steady state. The use of methanol for denitrification has resulted in a flux of 26.3 kg C/month into the aquarium and, as predicted, an increase in Ocean Tank DIC stock has been observed without any additions of sodium bicarbonate. Our approach can be used to model carbon and nitrogen balances in closed seawater facilities that host heterotrophic organisms and operate either with or without a biological denitrification system.'),(7,'Marine water','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','Inorganic granular material','Backwash waters from nitrifying filters','nan','Aerobic','Ethanol','Nitrate','60','nan','2400','nan','nan','The submerged filter resulted in an increased denitrification rate. However, bacterial growth tends to clog the packging which resulted in it having to be washed every three days.','Sauthier et al., 1998','Biological denitrification applied to a marine closed aquaculture system.','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0043135497004065','The denitrification of marine effluents was tested using a technology involving immobilized denitrifying bacteria on granular material. To ensure efficient denitrification, an organic carbon addition was needed. The denitrification rate was quantified in the pilot-unit working as a batch fermentor. A first order kinetic model according to the nitrate nitrogen concentration was found and the rate coefficient is an increasing function of the TOC/N(NO鈭?) ratio, with an optimum ratio of 1聽g聽g鈭?. Smaller values led to a nitrite production which was nevertheless oxidized in the treatment line; higher values could lead to the appearance of toxic sulphides. Working on stationary hydraulic loads, the treatment capacity of the unit was about 2.4 kgN(NO鈭?) m鈭?聽j鈭?. It was necessary to wash the packing once every 3 days. The malfunctioning of the unit could be avoided by the oxidation-reduction potential control.'),(8,'Seawater','Recirculating aquaculture systems Heterotrophic Denitrification','Packed bed','Fiber type plastic','Alcaligenes sp.','Japanese Flounder (Paralichthys olivaceus)','Aerobic','Glucose','Nitrate','52-310','nan','41','nan','nan','The closed seawater recirculation system coupled with a denitrification tank is a cost-effective technique that helped maintain a good water quality that enabled the culturing of Japanese Flounder.','Honda et al., 1993','High Density Rearing of Japanese Flounder, Paralichthys olivaceus with a Closed Seawater Recirculation System Equipped with a Denitrification Unit.','nan','https://www.jstage.jst.go.jp/article/aquaculturesci1953/41/1/41_1_19/_pdf','Rearing experiment of Japanese flounder was carried out under high density condition using a 2.25 m3 of closed seawater recirculation system equipped with a denitrification unit. After 10 months of rearing, fish grew to 501 g of mean body weight (initial: 9g). The total fish weight in the system became 97.6 kg, and the density per unit water volume in the system reached 43.4 kg/m3. Total amount of seawater used was 2.91 m3, then the product per unit volume of seawater used was 33.5 kg/m3. The aerobic filter of the system operated satisfactorily and both ammonia and nitrite concentrations of rearing water were maintained at less than 1 mg-N/l almost through the experimental period. The denitrification unit worked efficiently and nitrate concentration decreased from 314.6 mg-N/l to 51.9 mg-N/l duaring the experimental period. These results demonstrate that intensive culture of Japanese flounder under high density condition without wasteful use of seawater for rearing is possible by using the closed seawater recirculation system equipped with the denitrification unit.'),(9,'Marine water','Marine Recirculating aquaculture systems (RAS)','nan','PHBV granules','Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclasticus','nan','Aerobic','PHBV','Nitrate','nan','nan','nan','Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclasticus RAD-2','16S rRNA gene','Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclasticus RAD-2, was isolated from a long-term PHBV-supported denitrification reactor that operated under alternate aerobic/anoxic conditions for marine RAS-effluent treatment. Have the ability to utilize of various biodegradable polymers  as sole carbon','Kong et al., 2018','Denitrification-Potential Evaluation and Nitrate-Removal-Pathway Analysis of Aerobic Denitrifier Strain Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclasticus RAD-2.','nan','https://www.mdpi.com/2073-4441/10/10/1298','An aerobic denitrifier was isolated from a long-term poly (3-hydroxybutyrate-co-3-hydroxyvalerate) PHBV-supported denitrification reactor that operated under alternate aerobic/anoxic conditions. The strain was identified as聽Marinobacter hydrocarbonoclasticus聽RAD-2 based on 16S rRNA-sequence phylogenetic analysis. Morphology was observed by scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and phylogenetic characteristics were analyzed with the API 20NE test. Strain RAD-2 showed efficient aerobic denitrification ability when using NO3鈭?N or NO2鈭?N as its only nitrogen source, while heterotrophic nitrification was not detected. The average NO3鈭?N and NO2鈭?N removal rates were 6.47 mg/(L路h)and 6.32 mg/(L路h), respectively. Single-factor experiments indicated that a 5:10 C/N ratio, 25鈥?0 掳C temperature, and 100鈥?50 rpm rotation speed were the optimal conditions for aerobic denitrification. Furthermore, the denitrifying gene聽napA聽had the highest expression on a transcriptional level, followed by the denitrifying genes聽nirS聽and聽nosZ. The聽norB聽gene was found to have significantly low expression during the experiment. Overall, great aerobic denitrification ability makes the RAD-2 strain a potential alternative in enhancing nitrate management for marine recirculating aquaculture system (RAS) practices.聽View Full-Text'),(10,'Marine aquarium','Fish-culture systems','Fluidized bed','Alginate beads','Pseudomonas sp. JR12','Cichlids (Oreochromis mossambicus)','nan','Immobilized starch','Nitrate','nan','nan','62','nan','nan','Alginate beads containing an immobilized denitrifying bacterium and  immobilized starch can be used for removal of nitrate from water systems.','Tal et al., 2003','Nitrate Removal in Aquariums by Immobilized聽Pseudomonas.','https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12790671/','https://aiche.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1021/bp0200088','Biological denitrification of nitrate to nitrogen gas was examined in a freshwater and a marine aquarium. Nitrate removal in the aquarium water was accomplished with denitrifiers immobilized in a freeze鈥恉ried, alginate鈥恠tarch matrix. Starch served as a bacterial carbon source and cellular matrix鈥恠trengthening filler. Freeze鈥恉ried beads were placed in canisters through which nitrate鈥恟ich aquarium water was recirculated. The freshwater aquarium (100 L) contained goldfish (Carassius auratus聽) at a total biomass of 390 g, whereas cichlids (Oreochromis mossambicus聽) were kept at a similar stocking density in the marine aquarium. Denitrification resulted in low ambient nitrate concentrations in both aquariums. The specific nitrate removal rate of the freshwater beads was significantly higher (50 渭g of NO3鈥怤/bead/day) than that of seawater beads (5 渭g of NO3鈥怤/bead/day). Differences in ambient nitrate concentrations between both aquariums and diffusion limitation of nitrate to the active denitrification sites within the beads might explain these observed differences.'),(11,'Seawater','Sulfur-driven denitrification (SDN) systems','SDN reactor','Sterivex filter聽','Thiobacillus thioparus;  strains of the Epsilonproteobacterium Sulfurimonas; Gammaproteobacterial sulfur oxidizers of the Thiotrichales and Chromatiales, and a relative of Sedimenticola thiotaurini','nan','Anaerobic','Sulfur; Aragonite','Nitrate','nan','nan','nan','Consortium','16S rRNA gene; Shotgun DNA; RNA sequencing','A consortium of denitrifers capabale of coupling sulfur oxidation to denintrification was identified suggesting there is a potential dependencies amongst the SDN members in the denitrification system. These results provide a framework for potential manipulation of SDN reactor systems to maximize nitrate removal efficiency by adjusting physical parameters, changing the hydraulic retention time and microbial seeding. ','Burns  et al., 2018','Broad Phylogenetic Diversity Associated With Nitrogen Loss Through Sulfur Oxidation in a Large Public Marine Aquarium.','https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30097447/','https://aem.asm.org/content/84/20/e01250-18.long','Denitrification by sulfur-oxidizing bacteria is an effective nitrate removal strategy in engineered aquatic systems. However, the community taxonomic and metabolic diversity of sulfur-driven denitrification (SDN) systems, as well as the relationship between nitrate removal and SDN community structure, remains underexplored. This is particularly true for SDN reactors applied to marine aquaria, despite the increasing use of this technology to supplement filtration. We applied 16S rRNA gene, metagenomic, and metatranscriptomic analyses to explore the microbial basis of SDN reactors operating on Georgia Aquarium\'s Ocean Voyager, the largest indoor closed-system seawater exhibit in the United States. The exhibit\'s two SDN systems vary in water retention time and nitrate removal efficiency. The systems also support significantly different microbial communities. These communities contain canonical SDN bacteria, including a strain related to聽Thiobacillus thioparus聽that dominates the system with the higher water retention time and nitrate removal but is effectively absent from the other system. Both systems contain a wide diversity of other microbes whose metagenome-assembled genomes contain genes of SDN metabolism. These include hundreds of strains of the epsilonproteobacterium聽Sulfurimonas, as well as gammaproteobacterial sulfur oxidizers of the聽Thiotrichales聽and聽Chromatiales, and a relative of聽Sedimenticola聽thiotaurini聽with complete denitrification potential. The SDN genes are transcribed and the taxonomic richness of the transcript pool varies markedly among the enzymatic steps, with some steps dominated by transcripts from noncanonical SDN taxa. These results indicate complex and variable SDN communities that may involve chemical dependencies among taxa as well as the potential for altering community structure to optimize nitrate removal.'),(12,'Fresh seawater','RAS single-sludge denitrification','Activated-sludge type reactor','nan','Activated sludge','Gilthead seabream (Sparus Aurata)','Anaerobic/aerobic','Volatile fatty acids from Back-Wash Organic Matter (BWOM), intrinsic organic solids','Nitrate','nan','590.0','Delete','nan','nan','A 鈥榮ingle-sludge鈥?denitrification system, was developed where production of VFA from biosolids and denitrification occur in a single, mixed reactor. Study focused on denitrification in RAS using the intrinsic solids as the energy source. Developed a conceptual stoichiometry-based model of a RAS single-sludge denitrification reactor based on the principles known from activated sludge wastewater treatment modeling.','Klas et al., 2006','Development of a single-sludge denitrification method for nitrate removal from RAS effluents: Lab-scale results vs. model prediction.','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0044848606004339','A lab-scale activated-sludge type reactor was used to induce denitrification by using the organic solid waste of a typical Recirculating Aquaculture System (RAS) as the electron donor (鈥楽ingle-sludge denitrification鈥?. The results were compared with the predictions of a stoichiometry-based model. As predicted by the model, reactor\'s performance was found to be strongly related to the mean solids retention time (SRT) employed. Measured denitrification rates conformed very well to model predictions. High nitrate removal rates ofup to 590 mg N (Lreactord d)鈭? were recorded at a relatively low SRT of4 d. Oxygen, that entered the reactor via both atmospheric diffusion and with the stream used to simulate the influent from a fish tank, reduced the amount of organic matter available for denitrification, resulting in lower denitrification rates. This interference was more significant when the system was operated at the longer SRTs. Most of the excess ammonia released to the aqueous phase through ammonification was oxidized (presumably by anammox bacteria) under the prevailing anoxic conditions, resulting in very low effluent TAN concentrations. Phosphate release to the aqueous phase was significantly lower than predicted, suggesting above-typical microbial P assimilation. Reaction kinetics was found to be zero order with respect to nitrate at concentrations ofabove 1.5 to 2.0 mg N L鈭?. Taken together the findings indicate that intensive single-sludge denitrification for treating RAS effluents is technically feasible, and that the process appears to be a cost-effective solution to reducing both the nutrient and the organic loads generated by intensive fish farms. The main advantages of the method include minimal formation of undesired by-products, small reactor volume and simple control and operation. Furthermore, the process is well described by a conceptual mathematical model, allowing its application as a part of any RAS design.'),(13,'Fish tank','RAS single-sludge denitrification','Upflow anaerobic sludge-blanket reactor','Biofilter with BIO-BLOK','Activated sludge','Rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss)','Anaerobic','Volatile fatty acids from organic biosolids','Nitrate','nan','23.0','nan','nan','nan','The single-sludge concept was further developed, adapting it for end-of-pipe treatment of fish farming effluents and adding an extra step which separates VFA production from the denitrification reactor in a hydrolysis tank. ','Suhr et al., 2014','End-of-pipe single-sludge denitrification in pilot-scale recirculating aquaculture systems.','nan','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0144860914000569','A step toward environmental sustainability of recirculat aquaculture systems (RAS) is implementation of single-sludge denitrification, a process eliminating nitrate from the aqueous environment while reducing the organic matter discharge simultaneously. Two 1700聽L pilot-scale RAS systems each with a 85聽L denitrification (DN) reactor treating discharged water and hydrolyzed solid waste were setup to test the kinetics of nitrate and COD removal. Nitrate removal and COD reduction efficiency was measured at two different DN-reactor sludge ages (high聽胃X: 33鈥?2 days and low聽胃X: 17鈥?3 days). Nitrate and total N (NO3鈭捖?聽NO2鈭捖?聽NH4+) removal of the treated effluent water ranged from 73鈥?9% and 60鈥?5% during the periods, respectively, corresponding to an overall maximum RAS nitrate removal of approximately 75%. The specific nitrate removal rate increased from 17 to 23聽mg NO3鈭?N (g聽TVS聽d)鈭?聽and the maximal potential DN rate (measured at laboratory ideal conditions) increased correspondingly from 64鈥?8聽mg NO3鈭?N (g聽TVS聽d)鈭?聽to 247鈥?94聽mg NO3鈭?N (g聽TVS聽d)鈭?聽at high and low聽胃X, respectively. Quantification of denitrifiers in the DN-reactors by qPCR showed only minor differences upon the altered sludge removal practice. The hydrolysis unit improved the biodegradability of the solid waste by increasing volatile fatty acid COD content 74鈥?6%. COD reductions in the DN-reactors were 64鈥?0%. In conclusion, this study showed that single-sludge denitrification was a feasible way to reduce nitrate discharge from RAS, and higher DN rates were induced at lower sludge age/increased sludge removal regime. Improved control and optimization of reactor DN-activity may be achieved by further modifying reactor design and management scheme as indicated by the variation in and between the two DN-reactors.'),(14,'Fish digestion basin','Recirculating mariculture system based on sulphur driven denitrification','Fluidized bed','nan','Activated sludge','nan','Anaerobic','Sodium sulfide','Nitrate','nan','nan','nan','nan','nan','Presence of sulfide benefitted the overall system performance of a mariculture recirculating system by induction of autotrophic denitrification. The ratio of electron donor (sulfide) to electron acceptor (nitrate) plays an important role in the formation of end products and intermediate products of the sulfide oxidation and nitrate reduction pathways.','Sher et al., 2008','Sulfide-induced nitrate reduction in the sludge of an anaerobic digester of a zero-discharge recirculating mariculture system.','https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18718629/','https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0043135408003072','The anaerobic digester is a vital component in a zero-discharge mariculture system as therein most of the organic matter is mineralized and nitrogen-containing compounds are converted to gaseous N(2). Although denitrification is a major respiratory process in this nitrate-rich treatment stage, also sulfate respiration takes place and may cause undesirable high sulfide concentrations in the effluent water. To examine the effect of sulfide on nitrate reduction, in situ depth profiles of inorganic nitrogen and sulfur compounds were determined. Additionally, nitrate reduction was examined as a function of ambient sulfide concentrations in sludge collected from different locations in the anaerobic reactor. Depth profiles showed high concentrations of nitrate and low concentrations of sulfide and ammonia in the aqueous layer of the reactor. A sharp decrease of nitrate and an increase in sulfide and ammonia concentrations was measured at the water-sludge interface. Nitrate reduction was highest in this interface zone with rates of up to 8.05+/-0.57 micromol NO(3)(-)h(-1)g((sludge))(-1). Addition of sulfide increased the nitrate reduction rate at all sludge depths, pointing to the important role of autotrophic denitrification in the anaerobic reactor. Dissimilatory nitrate reduction to ammonia (DNRA) was found to be low in all sludge layers but was enhanced when sludge was incubated at high sulfide concentrations. Although nitrate reduction rates increased as a result of sulfide addition to sludge samples, no differences in nitrate reduction rates were observed between the samples incubated with different initial sulfide concentrations. This as opposed to sulfide oxidation rates, which followed Michaelis-Menten enzymatic kinetics. Partial oxidation of sulfide to elemental sulfur instead of a complete oxidation to sulfate, could explain the observed patterns of nitrate reduction and sulfide oxidation in sludge incubated with different initial sulfide concentrations.');
/*!40000 ALTER TABLE `denitrifications_app_marinesystem` ENABLE KEYS */;
UNLOCK TABLES;
/*!40103 SET TIME_ZONE=@OLD_TIME_ZONE */;

/*!40101 SET SQL_MODE=@OLD_SQL_MODE */;
/*!40014 SET FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS=@OLD_FOREIGN_KEY_CHECKS */;
/*!40014 SET UNIQUE_CHECKS=@OLD_UNIQUE_CHECKS */;
/*!40101 SET CHARACTER_SET_CLIENT=@OLD_CHARACTER_SET_CLIENT */;
/*!40101 SET CHARACTER_SET_RESULTS=@OLD_CHARACTER_SET_RESULTS */;
/*!40101 SET COLLATION_CONNECTION=@OLD_COLLATION_CONNECTION */;
/*!40111 SET SQL_NOTES=@OLD_SQL_NOTES */;

-- Dump completed on 2020-06-29  8:48:58
